Guide to the Duke University Union Reference Collection, 1962-ongoing
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Duke University Union Reference collection 1962-ongoing
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. University Archives
0.7 Linear Feet approx. 600 Items
The Duke University Union Reference Collection contains files of printed materials documenting Union administration and programming. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Duke University Union Reference Collection was compiled by the University Archives from a variety of resources for use in reference and research.
Historical Note
The Duke University Union, founded in 1954 as the Duke Student Union, has as its purpose promoting social, recreational, cultural, educational and spiritual activities at Duke. Membership is now open to all members of the Duke community. At present (2009), an executive group and program directors administer the Union.
Collection Overview
This collection contains files about the activities of the Union's administrative body and its programming committees. The collection includes clippings, flyers, calendars, program schedules, publicity postcards, printed budgets, newsletters, and form letters. The bulk dates are 1980-2000. Topics include regular Union programming and special events such as SpringFest, OktoberFest, and scavenger hunts.
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Administration, 1982-2001 (Box 1)
  - Budgets, 1984-
  - Clippings
  - History, circa 1962-
  - Newsletters, 1989-
  - Publicity and mailings
  - Reunions and alumni
  - The State of Your Union, circa 1971
  - Art Events Committee
  - Cable 13
  - Cable 13--Duke Yearlook
  - Craft Center
  - Fine Arts Committee
  - Freewater Films--Calendars
  - Freewater Films--Clippings
  - Freewater Films-Flyers
  - Galleries Committee
  - Grateful Dead, 1982--clippings
  - Major Speakers Committee
  - On Stage Committee
  - Performing Arts Committee
  - Performing Arts Committee: Broadway at Duke, circa 1972-
  - Quadrangle Pictures
  - Special Events Committee
  - Special Events - Scavenger hunts
  - Symposium Committee
  - Visual Arts Committee
  - Miscellaneous flyers
  - Duplicates